Email: <u>cs.bradbury@outlook.com</u> Mobile: +44 7383514483

Portfolio: https://calum-bradbury.herokuapp.com/

Calum Bradbury

58 Priory Walk, Leicester, UK, LE3 3PP

Summary

I am a driven and adaptable Masters of Electrical & Electronic Engineering (MEng) graduate with real-world work experience in a range of positions. Analytically minded and very enthusiastic about technology, I have experience in a wide assortment of software and programming languages. I thrive off positive results and solving complex problems.

Education

MEng Electrical & Electronic Engineering (Hons), University of Nottingham, UK Sept 2016 – June 2020

- Achieved degree classification: First-Class Honours (1st).
- Recipient of the 2020 Electrical & Electronic Engineering Prize awarded annually to the graduating student "adjudged to have made the most commendable progress during the whole of the degree course".
- Relevant modules include Advanced Computational Engineering (87%), Scalable Cross-Platform Software Design (72%), Computer Aided Engineering (71%) and Discrete Mathematics (Canadian grade A).

Study year abroad Concordia University, QC, Canada Sept 2017–May 2018

- Demonstrated the commitment to personal improvement and the drive to take on new challenges through studying internationally.
- Showcased the ability to adapt to new situations and improved communication skills in another language through living in a province where French is the official language.

Professional Experience

Student IT Support Tutor University of Nottingham Medical School, UK Sept 2019 – May 2020

• Developed customer service and technical skills through supporting medical school staff and students at the Queen's Medical Centre hospital with the university IT services, as well as any issues with personal and professional electronic devices.

Software Developer Power Vigilance, Nottingham, UK 29th April 2019 – 10th May 2019

- Two-week internship working on the development of a new online client portal for a small Nottingham based start-up Company.
- Successfully suggested and implemented multiple new features to the client portal including a freshly designed progress bar for the illustration of power usage in a client's building.

Advanced Manufacturing Labs Intern University of Nottingham, UK June 2018 – Sept 2018

- Summer internship in the University of Nottingham Advanced Manufacturing Laboratory.
 Tasked with the design of a bespoke end-effector for a robot to process bio-materials with, in order to allow a local company to automate their current processes.
- Experience gained using Python, Robot Operating Software (ROS) and SOLIDWORKS.
- Successfully used 3D CAD software (SOLIDWORKS) to design the end-effector and programmed the robot to operate it in order to process bio-materials taken from a local hospital (Queens Medical Centre, Nottingham, UK).

Operations Technician

Caterpillar Inc, Leicester, UK.

Sept 2014 – July 2016

- Employed full time within a team of colleagues manufacturing hydraulic values for backhoe loader diggers.
- Worked effectively and diligently in a high pressure and fast-paced environment.

Volunteer Experience

Library Assistant Leicester Forest East Community Library, Leicester, UK June 2019 – Sept 2019

- Summer volunteer at local library assisting patrons with the online catalogue system.
- Utilized strong attention to detail to organize library shelves and restock returned books.
- Assisted patrons with any IT queries and issues.

Course Representative University of Nottingham, UK Sept 2016 – June 2017

- Course representative in first year of undergraduate degree tasked with reporting any issues with the course to the heads of the department.
- Responsibilities included being the first port of call for students if they had problems of any kind and gathering feedback to be communicated at monthly meetings with lecturers and heads of the department.

Additional Skills & Qualifications

- C/C++
- JavaScript
- HTML5 & CSS3/Sass
- React.js (Hooks, React Router etc)
- Git

- Lumerical Photonic Simulation Software
- Assembly
- MATLAB
- SOLIDWORKS
- Full UK Driving License

Additional Interests

Latin & Ballroom Dancing University of Nottingham DanceSport Team Sept 2019 – May 2020

- As a Member of the University of Nottingham DanceSport Team I competed in multiple national Ballroom & Latin dance competitions. Including the Inter Varsity Dance Championships (IVDC) at the Winter Gardens in Blackpool.
- Demonstrated discipline, dedication, and willingness to step out of my comfort zone when competing in front of hundreds or thousands of spectators.

Studying French

• I thoroughly enjoy studying the French language and have done so at night school whilst working full time and during my final year of University. Again, demonstrating my desire and drive to always learn and challenge myself.